# MEGAN HUTCHINSON

+1 (647) 563-7395 · hutchinsonmegan20@gmail.com ·LinkedIn

I am a mid-level analytically-minded IT professional with over six years of experience in Quality Assurance and over two years of experience in Data analysis. My proficiency lies in translating intricate business requirements into precise technical specifications, mitigating any potential for misunderstanding. I specialize in analyzing, testing and implementing new and updated software programs focusing on quality assurance and testing. Recognized for my adept problem-solving skills, adaptability and effective communication. My skill set extends to technology and business requirements definition, test-driven development and proficient troubleshooting.

### STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

Python	CRM	Github	Snowflake
MS-SQL	Microsoft Office Suite	Atlassian Products: Jira, Confluence	IBM Cognos
Tableau	Power BI	HIVE	R

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Maple Leaf Sports and Entertainment Quick Service Supervisor

July 2022 - Present

Demonstrate exceptional leadership by overseeing and organizing the operations for the front-of-house and back-of-house which helps in operational efficiency and fan satisfaction.

## Accomplishments:

- Supervise and coordinate the activities for both front-of-house and back-of-house personnel.
- Provides ongoing guidance to staff to help in improving performance which helps in providing excellent customer service.
- Addressed and resolved unforeseen issues involving fans, employees, hardware or emergencies that may arise during the shift.
- Troubleshoot communication errors in point-of-sale terminals and pin pads before escalation.
- Assign tasks, set schedules and ensure team members are adequately trained.

# Humber College Institute of Technology and Advanced Learning Research Assistant

May 2023 - November 2023

Analyzed public data to create and refine survey questions thus identifying hiring process gaps.

#### Accomplishments:

- Identified network effects for a staffing platform that helps in increasing its defensibility.
- Used data to create a better customer experience by identifying flaws in the hiring process and resolving them with this staffing application.
- Used survey data to assist the company in decision making which will prepare it for expansion.
- Utilized strong analytical skills to examine the hiring processes being used by companies to improve upon accuracy and efficiency taking it from 36 days to 6 days maximum.

# TD Bank Group Business Insights Analyst (Co-Op)

January 2023 - June 2023

Created log file standards, using Python, after observing the trends within the various log files and comparing it to the requirements listed for the new system.

#### Accomplishments:

- Utilized Python to read, analyze, clean and debug logs and artifacts to conduct root cause analysis and develop solutions.
- Used Visio to generate detailed and summarised process flow diagrams for the logging system developed.
- Facilitated knowledge transfer sessions along with documentation for the logging system developed.
- Utilized tools such as Jira and Confluence to manage and track the process of the project task and also participated in daily standups, sprint planning and retrospects.

Translated application requirements into test cases and created detailed-oriented test plans to execute them.

#### Accomplishments:

- Assessed and prioritized project issues which helped to prevent inaccessibility of the system for users.
- Created and executed test cases and suites and recorded bugs found in Jira to allow stakeholders, developers and QA to monitor to status of the defect and its solution.
- Collaborated with various departments to define the project scope, and objectives and ensure it aligned with the business and project goals.
- Analysed technical requirements to ensure it was aligned to Shopify's user needs and developed test
  cases according to industry best practices.

# eGov Jamaica Limited Quality Assurance Analyst

July 2019 - July 2021

Gathered requirements and developed business documents along with creating test plans and cases.

### Accomplishments:

- Created and executed SQL queries to analyze the pension eligibility data which were presented using reports where trends were identified which helped in delivering data-driven solutions.
- Prioritized data quality by creating UI Automation test scripts to verify the various text fields accept the data that they should which were versioned using GitHub.
- Developed technical specifications and business requirement documents through collaboration with stakeholders via requirement meetings to deliver data-driven solutions.
- Attended brainstorming sessions which helped in informed decision-making on the solution that should be implemented and prioritization of which issue should be resolved first.

# Insurance Company of the West Indies Quality Assurance and Systems Analyst

October 2017 - July 2019

Resolve computer or applications issues that are either logged by phone or email along with troubleshooting internal computer and quote engine application issues.

## Accomplishments:

- Spearheaded and participated in the complete rollout of the new ticketing software for the IT help desk.
- Managed and maintained the helpdesk ticketing system, establishing SLAs based on issue severity.
- Resolved hardware and software issues for internal users promptly and effectively.
- Collaborated with the underwriting department to understand the reports being required and with the developers to validate that the report met the objectives outlined.
- Adhered to release management processes by attending and presenting the new version of the application to be deployed and the reason behind its development.

## **EDUCATION**

**Humber College Institute of Technology & Advanced Learning**Ontario Post Graduate Certificate, Business Insights and Analytics

September 2021 - April 2023

University of Technology, Jamaica

August 2012 - May 2016

February 2020

March 2021

March 2023

September 2023

September 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computing major Computer Science (Honors)

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

ISTQB Foundation Level Certification
Scrum Fundamentals Certification
Tableau Fundamentals Certification
Snowflake Hands-On Essentials - Data Warehouse
Snowflake Hands-On Essentials - Data Applications